<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hashed &amp; Signed</title>
    <link>https://shanedeconinck.be/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hashed &amp; Signed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 21:22:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://shanedeconinck.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Twee maanden in Japan, vertoefd zonder plan</title>
      <link>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/2-maanden-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 21:22:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/2-maanden-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>Het zit er bijna op. Twee maanden in Japan, vertoefd zonder plan.&#xA;Ik heb een appartementje gehuurd in Tokyo. Wat even weinig specifiek is als zeggen “In Vlaanderen”. Want Tokyo heeft geen specifiek centrum, het is een aaneensluiting van vele buurten. Dus, meer specifiek, heb ik 2 maanden in Ootsuka gewoond, dat vlak naast Ikebukuro ligt.&#xA;In december vorig jaar kwam ik voor de eerste keer naar Japan. Reeds mijn hele leven fascineert Japan me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most DAOs fail. Long live DAOs!</title>
      <link>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/most-daos-fail-long-live-daos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 21:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/most-daos-fail-long-live-daos/</guid>
      <description>Smart Contracts The idea of smart contracts was conceived in the late &amp;rsquo;90s by Nick Szabo, a computer scientist, legal scholar, and cryptographer. In 1996 he published the article Smart Contracts: Building Blocks for Digital Free Markets and in 1997 the article The Idea of Smart Contracts.&#xA;Szabo explored the potential of using cryptographic techniques to bring about self-executing contracts and decentralized mechanisms for enforcing contractual clauses. His vision was to embed contractual agreements into the programming of digital systems, thereby reducing the need for traditional legal enforcement mechanisms and intermediaries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Account Abstraction, a Game Changer for Web3&#39;s UX issues</title>
      <link>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/account-abstraction-game-changer-web3s-ux-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:16:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/account-abstraction-game-changer-web3s-ux-issues/</guid>
      <description>The promise of Web3 lies in its potential to create a decentralized internet where users have control over their data and transactions. However, the path to this new dawn is obstructed by significant user experience (UX) challenges. The complexity of managing gas fees in Ether, the fear of losing cryptographic keys, and the technical hurdles in setting up multisig accounts have all been significant barriers to widespread adoption.&#xA;In the Ethereum ecosystem, users traditionally interact with the network through two types of accounts: Externally Owned Accounts (EOAs) and contract accounts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How enterprise blockchain is benefiting from innovations in the Wild W3st</title>
      <link>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/how-enterprise-blockchain-benefiting-from-innovations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 20:52:34 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/how-enterprise-blockchain-benefiting-from-innovations/</guid>
      <description>The emergence of blockchain networks On October 31, 2008 Satoshi Nakamoto published the Bitcoin whitepaper. Two months later, the Bitcoin genesis block was mined. Interestingly, we still don&amp;rsquo;t know the identity of Satoshi, which I hope will remain a mystery forever.&#xA;Now, 14 years later, the novel technology called &amp;lsquo;blockchain&amp;rsquo; is still an area of excitement, disappointment, hope, confusion and heated debate. It turns out that designing decentralized networks and building upon them is a subtle art with many parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why we should stop bullying Bitcoin&#39;s Proof of Work for its energy consumption</title>
      <link>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/why-we-should-stop-bullying-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:22:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shanedeconinck.be/posts/why-we-should-stop-bullying-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>The trading price of #Bitcoin had a downfall during the last years, but is seeing a strong comeback these days. This will make it an interesting topic again for media, and no doubt the comparisons to the energy consumption of whole countries will be mentioned with excitement and anger. How dare we spoil all this for a coin that we even can&amp;rsquo;t touch?!&#xA;To me, however, Bitcoin is interesting every day.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
